

CONTACT

(505) 610 1728

🏠 Albuquerque, NM

EDUCATION

B.A. MASS COMMUNICATIONS

2009

University of New Mexico Albuquerque, NM

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Blog Writing/Editing
- Content Counseling
- Customer Service
- Editorial Calendar Management
- Efficiency Coaching
- New Hire Training/Onboarding
- Press Release Writing/Editing
- Proofreading
- Project Implementation
- Search Engine Optimization
- Social Media Curation
- Team Management
- Workflow Management

RAQUELA MARIE PARKER

Manager, Audience & Journalist Engagement

ABOUT

I'm a top-performing content and media relations specialist. I'm known for being consistent, dependable, and self-motivated. I have deep knowledge of press release writing and editing, blogging, and Search Engine Optimization. I have been recognized for content counseling, accurate and efficient editing, project management, and training.

In May 2019, I took over responsibilities for Cision PR Newswire's Audience Relations team, including management of the media- and blogger-focused blog, Beyond Bylines. I manage the editorial calendar and work with more than 10 authors to keep the blog consistently updated with 3-6 new posts each week.

I also manage an internship program with nearly 20 individuals. The team monitors and writes press releases, curates social media accounts, and writes regular blog posts to increase visibility and engagement for PR Newswire client press releases.

EXPERIENCE

MANAGER, AUDIENCE & JOURNALIST ENGAGEMENT

Cision PR Newswire | Albuquerque, NM | May 2018 - Present

- Proofreads and quality checks blog posts for journalist- and mediafocused blog Beyond Bylines and PR Newswire
- Writes regular media-focused blog posts covering industry trends, best practices, news, and writing tips
- Creates and maintains landing pages and resource sections on the PR Newswire website
- Manages an Industry Ambassadors program with nearly 20 individuals. The team monitors thousands of press releases for given industries, curates social media profiles, and writes regular press release roundups and blog nosts
- Writes and distributes a monthly external newsletter for Beyond Bylines that reaches nearly 100K media workers
- Manages social media pages for Beyond Bylines, PR Newswire for Journalists, and PR Newswire on Facebook, Twitter, and LinkedIn
- Maintains a team page on the company's intranet space with resource links, documents, and contact details
- Compiles and analyzes press release volume data weekly for timely events and trending topics to share with journalists

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Adobe Analytics
- Adobe Experience Manager
- Adobe Photoshop
- Asana
- Canva
- Eloqua
- Falcon.io
- Hootsuite
- NewsCred
- · Microsoft Office Suite
- PR Newswire for Journalists
- Salesforce
- Semrush
- SharePoint
- Social Media (Facebook, Instagram, LinkedIn, Pinterest, Snapchat, Twitter)
- Uberflip
- WordPress
- Wrike
- Yoast

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Generated 650K press release views and 430K clicks in 6month period
- Beyond Bylines named to Feedspot Top 50 Journalism Blogs 2019-2023
- 2018 Q4 Team "Cisionary" Award Recipient
- 100% Accuracy 2017
- Top Performer 2016/2017

WRITING SAMPLES

- View previous blog posts at www.authory.com/RockyParker
- Press releases available at https://www.prnewswire.com/ne ws/pr-newswire/

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR CUSTOMER CONTENT SPECIALIST

PR Newswire | Albuquerque, NM | Sept 2010 - May 2018

- Proofread and quality checked press releases
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO) Expert: Participant and lead for an internal SEO & Content Discovery Certification project, counseling internal and external teams and individuals on content best practices. Performed counseling for CareerBuilder, Cohn & Wolfe, Amendola Communications, and more.
- Lead new-hire trainings, assisted with onboarding, mentored new specialists
- Participated in internal internships, product advocate programs
- Aided clients in analyzing and interpreting release performance reports, including release pickup, engagement, and industry benchmark data
- Top Performer in Efficiency: Responsible for observing specialists, compiling the data and recommending new and follow-up trainings to help increase efficiency and improve individual and group processes
- Regularly worked with management to implement new workflow processes

CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE

Mr. Handyman | Albuquerque, NM | Feb 2010 - Sept 2010

- Troubleshooted customer service issues
- Coordinated technician schedules
- Managed day-to-day office operations
- Created and maintained an office manual of standard operating procedures

PUBLIC RELATIONS INTERN

Rick Johnson & Co. | Albuquerque, NM | Jan 2009 - May 2009

- Assisted Public Relations team with the writing of press releases for national and local clients, including McDonald's and Presbyterian Health Care
- Created and updated media contact matrices using MediaAtlas
- Maintained client clipping books
- Conducted research for various projects for the Public Relations team